Michael Jung

Software Engineer

■ themikejung@gmail.com

mhtjung.github.io

github.com/mhtjung

in linkedin.com/in/themikejjung

₽ PROFILE

I'm a software engineer in the San Diego, CA area with multiple years of experience in technologies including Go, JavaScript, React, PostgreSQL, MongoDB. I've deployed projects to AWS, Digital Ocean, and Heroku. Most recently, I designed and created Triage, a service for Kafka consumers that solves head-of-line blocking.

EXPERIENCE

Co-Creator, Software Engineer, Triage (team-triage.github.io)

2022 - present

Triage is an open-source consumer proxy for Apache Kafka that solves head-of-line blocking caused by both poison pills and non-uniform consumer latency. Head-of-line blocking exists in queue-like structures and can cause crash/restart cycles, slow consumption of messages, and increased consumer lag, ultimately denigrating system performance. Triage enables parallel consumption of a single Kafka partition, greatly mitigating if not curing these negative effects altogether.

- Built Triage ☑ using Go, gRPC, Docker, and AWS
- Enabled parallel consumption of a single Kafka partition via concurrency in Go
- Resolved consumer delay and crash/restart cycles caused by poison pills
- · Resolved consumption latency caused by slow external services
- Constructed a deployment command line interface, distributed as an NPM package (triage-cli [7])
- Implemented Triage's client library in Go (triage-client-go ☑), used by consumer applications to interact with Triage
- Utilized gRPC for network communication, increasing message throughput and reducing network usage.
- Played a key role in the planning and implementation of Triage's application logic
- Collaborated with a fully remote team of engineers on a daily basis
- Authored technical case study ☐ for Triage, specifically design challenges and implementation sections

Software Engineer, Open Source

2021 - 2022

Build open source projects using Node.js, Vanilla JavaScript, Ruby, React, Express, PostgreSQL, MongoDB.

- Request Djinn An HTTP webhook inspector built using the MERN stack & PostgreSQL
- Notes A browser based note taking application build using the MERN stack
- Contacts Manager A simple light CRM for managing contacts built using the MVC pattern with NodeJS, Express, and Handlebars

Account Executive, HIPAA Vault

2017 – 2019

Managed the sales lifecycle for clients in the cloud healthcare space, closing over \$1MM in ARR

⊗ SKILLS

Languages & Frameworks (Go, Node.js, Vanilla JavaScript, React, Express, Ruby, Sinatra, SQL)

Tools (Apache Kafka, Docker/Dockerhub, Git/Github, HTTP, gRPC, NPM)

EDUCATION

Capstone Program, Launch School

BS, Business Management, Western Governor's University

2020

themikejung@gmail.com 1/1